<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Chakshu Dhannawat</title>
    <link>https://chakshu-dhannawat.github.io/Chakshu-Portfolio/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Chakshu Dhannawat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chakshu-dhannawat.github.io/Chakshu-Portfolio/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3D-Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://chakshu-dhannawat.github.io/Chakshu-Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chakshu-dhannawat.github.io/Chakshu-Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>This is not a finished project, instead something which I have worked on. I had researched various algorithms for 3d reconstruction. The different algorithms implemented were:
 NeRF, Used multiple 2d images of a object and also the camera angles/poses at which the 2d images were captured to generate a single 3d object. PIFuHD from facebook. Used to create 3d models from single human images.  You can find more similar repositories on my github profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML-Experimentation</title>
      <link>https://chakshu-dhannawat.github.io/Chakshu-Portfolio/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chakshu-dhannawat.github.io/Chakshu-Portfolio/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>This is also not a project, but instead a collection of google colab notebooks, where I try to test the recenly released machine learning models such as DALLE-2, Imagen, Language models such as BLOOM,GPT-3 etc. I will be adding many more google colab files into this github repository in the future. This repository contains the experimentation that I will perform on the recent advancements in AI. Mostly related to the recent research papers released in the community, and the machine learning models that have become quite popular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retinal Image Analysis</title>
      <link>https://chakshu-dhannawat.github.io/Chakshu-Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chakshu-dhannawat.github.io/Chakshu-Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Did this project under the guidance of Professor Dr. Anil Kumar Tiwari from IIT Jodhpur. The motivation of this project was to create a software which would assist in automated detection of retinal diseases taking the images of the retinas as input.
 Led a team of 3 members and implemented various deep learning algorithms related to Hypertensive Retinopathy detection. Implemented Retinal Vessel Segmentation and worked on image enhancement algorithms. Analyzed differentImage Classification models like VGG16, ResNet50, for detecting diseases from the images of the retinas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>